<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_fi_FI>
	    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ABHIJNANASAKUTALAM">
	        <Text>"Eilinen on vain unta;[NEWLINE]Huominen ainoastaan visio.[NEWLINE]Mutta elämällä hyvin tänään teet[NEWLINE]eilisestä onnellisuuden unta;[NEWLINE]ja jokaisesta huomisesta vision toivosta."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ADVENTURES_OF_HUCKLEBERRY">
	        <Text>"Vaan näenpä että minun täytyy kiiruhtaa territorioon ennen muita, sillä Sally-täti aikoo adoptoida ja sivistää minut, enkä voi sietää sitä. Tiedän jo millaista se on."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_AENEID">
	        <Text>"It is easy to go down into Hell;[NEWLINE]night and day the gates of dark Death stand wide;[NEWLINE]but to climb back again, to retrace one's steps to the upper air -[NEWLINE]there's the rub, the task."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ALICES_ADVANTURES">
	        <Text>"'But I don't want to go among mad people,' Alice remarked.[NEWLINE]'Oh, you can't help that,' said the Cat. 'We're all mad here. I'm mad. You're mad.'[NEWLINE]'How do you know I'm mad?' said Alice.[NEWLINE]'You must be,' said the Cat, 'or you wouldn't have come here.'"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_AZUL">
	        <Text>"Bagpipes of Spain, ye that can sing[NEWLINE]That which is sweetest to us in the Spring![NEWLINE]You first sing of gladness and then sing of pain[NEWLINE]As deep and as bitter as the billowed main."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_A_CHRISTMAS_CAROL">
	        <Text>"You may be an undigested bit of beef, a blot of mustard, a crumb of cheese, a fragment of underdone potato. There's more of gravy than of grave about you, whatever you are!"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_A_LA_RECHERCHE">
	        <Text>"There is no man, however wise, who has not at some point in his youth said things, or lived a life, the memory of which is so unpleasant to him that he would gladly expunge it. And yet he ought not entirely regret it, because he cannot be certain that he has indeed become a wise man."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_BAKHSHALI">
	        <Text>"Five merchants together buy a jewel. Its price is equal to half the money possessed by the first together with the money possessed by the others, or one-third of the money possessed by the second together with the moneys possessed by the others..."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_BARRACK_ROOM_BALLADS">
	        <Text>"And the first rude sketch that the world has seen[NEWLINE]was joy to his heart.[NEWLINE]Till the Devil whispered behind the leaves,[NEWLINE]'It's pretty, but is it art?'"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CANDIDE_OU_LOPTIMISME">
	        <Text>"Fools have a habit of believing that everything written by a famous author is admirable. For my part I read only to please myself and only what suits my taste."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CANTERBURY_TALES">
	        <Text>"Yet do not miss the moral, my good men.[NEWLINE]For Saint Paul says that all that's written well[NEWLINE]Is written down some useful truth to tell.[NEWLINE]Then take the wheat and let the chaff lie still."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CHAYKA">
	        <Text>"Why do I hear a note of sadness that wrings my heart in this cry of a pure soul? If at any time you should have need of my life, come and take it."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CHU_CI">
	        <Text>"Two monarchs then, who high renown received,[NEWLINE]followed the kingly way, their goal achieved.[NEWLINE]Two princes proud by lust their reign abused,[NEWLINE]sought easier path, and their own steps confused."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CODEX_BORGIA">
	        <Text>"Tezcatlipoca: He by whom we live. Lord of the Near and the Nigh."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_CODEX_PEREZ">
	        <Text>"The prophecy of Chilam Balam, the singer, of Cabal-chen, Mani. On 13 Ahau the katun will end in the time of the Itza, in the time of Tancah"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_DEAD_SEA">
	        <Text>"Tell them this, 'These gods, who did not make the heavens and the earth, will perish from the earth and from under the heavens.'"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_DIE_RAUBER">
	        <Text>"Not that I have any doubt but that justice would find me speedily enough if the powers above so ordained it. But she might surprise me in sleep, or overtake me in flight, or seize me with violence and the sword, and then I should have lost the only merit left me, that of making my death a free-will atonement."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_DIVINA_COMMEDIA">
	        <Text>"The hottest places in Hell are reserved for those who, in times of great moral crisis, maintain their neutrality."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_EL_INGENIOSO">
	        <Text>"'Now look, your grace,' said Sancho, 'what you see over there are not giants, but windmills, and what seems to be arms are just sails, that go around in the wind and turn the millstone.'[NEWLINE]'Obviously,' replied Don Quixote, 'you don't know much about adventures.'"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_FABLES">
	        <Text>"The tortoise plodded on and on. When the Hare awoke from his nap, he saw the Tortoise near the winning post. But he could not run fast enough in time to save the race. Then the Tortoise said, 'Slow and steady wins the race.'"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_FAUST">
	        <Text>"When scholars study a thing, they strive to kill it first, if it's alive; then they have the parts and the'be lost the whole, for the link that's missing was the living soul."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_FRANKENSTEIN">
	        <Text>"Learn from me, if not by my precepts, at least by my example, how dangerous is the acquirement of knowledge, and how much happier that man is who believes his native town to be the world, than he who aspires to become greater than his nature will allow."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_GENJI_MONOGATARI">
	        <Text>"One ought not to be unkind to a woman merely on account of her plainness, any more than one had a right to take liberties with her merely because she was handsome."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_GILGAMESH">
	        <Text>"I will set up my name in the place where the names of famous men are written, and where no man's name is written I will raise a monument to the gods."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_GIRART_DE_VIENNE">
	        <Text>"May God forbid the deed![NEWLINE]A King of France shall not be harmed by me![NEWLINE]If he forgives me, I'll be his man of liege,[NEWLINE]And hold from him all my lands in fief."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_HAMMURABI">
	        <Text>"196. If a man put out the eye of another man, his eye shall be put out."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_HONG_LOU_MENG">
	        <Text>"The cunning waste their pains;[NEWLINE]The wise men vex their brains;[NEWLINE]But the simpleton, who seeks no gains,[NEWLINE]With belly full, he wanders free,[NEWLINE]As drifting boat upon the sea."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_IL_CANZONIERE">
	        <Text>"How do you know, poor fool? Perhaps out there, somewhere, someone is sighing for your absence; and with this thought, my soul begins to breathe."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_JIN_PING_MEI">
	        <Text>"The passions evoked by clouds and rain,[NEWLINE]joining their heads and twining their necks,[NEWLINE]within the bed curtains. Truly:[NEWLINE]When feelings converge, one is apt to forget[NEWLINE]what happens to a brocade girdle."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_JUSHICHIJO_KEMPO">
	        <Text>"Harmony is to be valued, and the avoidance of wanton opposition to be honored...Then what is there which cannot be accomplished."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_KEDUKAN_BUKRIT">
	        <Text>"In the year 605 of the Saka calendar, on the eleventh day on the full moon of Waisaka, His Majesty took a boat to make a profit."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_KELLS">
	        <Text>"In the beginning was the Word...and the Word was made flesh, and dwelt among us."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_KOKIN_WAKASHU">
	        <Text>"Argent pearls[NEWLINE]Did my tears seem[NEWLINE]Yet with the passing years[NEWLINE]Chinese crimson[NEWLINE]Have they become"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LADY_CHATTERLEYS_LOVER">
	        <Text>"A woman has to live her life, or live to repent not having lived it."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LA_VIE_DE_GARGANTUA">
	        <Text>"Seeing how sorrow eats you, defeats you,[NEWLINE]I'd rather write about laughing than crying,[NEWLINE]For laughter makes men human, and courageous."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LEAVES_OF_GRASS">
	        <Text>"Oh Captain! My Captain! Our fearful trip is done,[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The ship has weather'd every rack; the prize we sought is won."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LES_MISERABLES">
	        <Text>"The greatest happiness in life is the conviction that we are loved - loved for ourselves, or rather, loved in spite of ourselves ... To love another person is to see the face of God."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LES_TROIS_MOUSQUETAIRES">
	        <Text>"All for one, one for all, that is our device."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LE_MORTE_DARTHUR">
	        <Text>"Yet some men say in many parts of England that King Arthur is not dead, but had by the will of our Lord Jesus into another place; and men say that he shall come again."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LINEAR_B">
	        <Text>"Thus saw Phugebris when the king appointed Augewas the do-mo-ko-ro...slaves women thirty-two...older girls five...younger girls fifteen...younger boys four"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_LYSISTRATA">
	        <Text>"You, man, are fool enough, it seems, to dare to war with women, when for your faithful ally you might win us easily."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MACBETH">
	        <Text>"Life ... is a tale[NEWLINE]Told by an idiot, full of sound and fury,[NEWLINE]Signifying nothing."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MAHABHARATA">
	        <Text>"To save the family, abandon a man;[NEWLINE]To save the village, abandon a family;[NEWLINE]To save the country, abandon a village;[NEWLINE]To save the soul, abandon the earth."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MARIA">
	        <Text>"I fell asleep sorrowful, filled with a vague foreboding of coming trouble. That lock of hair taken from a boy's head, that precaution of love against death, even in the presence of abounding life, caused my thoughts to wander all night about those scenes where I had passed, without knowing it, the happiest hours of my life."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MARTIN_FIERRO">
	        <Text>"I am a gaucho, and take this from me[NEWLINE]As my tongue explains it to you:[NEWLINE]For me the earth is a small place[NEWLINE]And could be bigger yet"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MASNAVI">
	        <Text>"Knock, and He'll open the door.[NEWLINE]Vanish, and He'll make you shine like the sun.[NEWLINE]Fall, and He'll raise you to the heavens.[NEWLINE]Become nothing, and He'll turn you into everything."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MAWANGDUI">
	        <Text>"Bloody Hemorrhoid. Boil thoroughly one male rat in urine. Hot press with the vapor."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_METAMORPHOSES">
	        <Text>"Happy is the man who has broken the chains which hurt the mind,[NEWLINE]and has given up worrying once and for all.[NEWLINE]Be patient and tough; one day this pain will be useful to you."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_MOBY_DICK">
	        <Text>"Call me Ishmael. Some years ago - never mind how long precisely - having little or no money in my purse, and nothing particular to interest me on shore, I thought I would sail about a little and see the watery part of the world."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_NAG_HAMMADI">
	        <Text>"But those whom he has anointed are the ones who have become perfect. For full jars are the ones that are anointed. But when the anointing of one is dissolved, it is emptied."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_NA_DNE">
	        <Text>"Happiness always looks small while you hold it in your hands, but let it go, and you learn at once how big and precious it is."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ODYSSEY">
	        <Text>"Men are so quick to blame the gods: they say[NEWLINE]that we devise their misery. But they[NEWLINE]themselves in their depravity design[NEWLINE]grief greater than the grief that fate assigns."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_OEDIPUS">
	        <Text>"Oedipus knew the famous riddles. He was a mighty king; he was the envy of everyone. Now he's struck a wave of terrible ruin. While you are alive, you must keep looking to your final day, and do not be happy 'til you pass life's boundary without suffering grief."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ORLANDO_FURIOSO">
	        <Text>"There never was such beauty in another man. Nature made him, and then broke the mold."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_PAPYRUS_ANI">
	        <Text>"Hail, oh ye who give cakes and ales to perfect souls in the House of Osiris, give ye cakes and ale twice each day to the soul of Osiris Ani, whose word is true before the gods, the Lords of Abydos."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_POEMS">
	        <Text>"Because I could not stop for Death -[NEWLINE]He kindly stopped for me -[NEWLINE]The carriage held but just Ourselves -[NEWLINE]And Immortality."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_PRESTIPLENIYE">
	        <Text>"Pain and suffering are always inevitable for a large intelligence and a deep heart. The really great men must, I think, have great sadness on earth."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_PRIDE_AND_PREJUDICE">
	        <Text>"I cannot fix on the hour, or the spot, or the look or the words, which laid the foundation. I was in the middle before I knew that I had begun."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_RAMAYAMA">
	        <Text>"Valmiki the Poet held all the moving world inside a water drop in his hand.[NEWLINE]The gods and saints from Heaven looked down,[NEWLINE]And Valmiki looked down at the gods in the morning of Time."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_RED_BADGE_OF_COURAGE">
	        <Text>"He vaguely desired to walk around and around the body and stare; the impulse of the living to try to read in dead eyes the answer to the Question."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_REVIZOR">
	        <Text>"It is no use to blame the looking glass if your face is awry."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_ROSETTA">
	        <Text>"...those who dwell in them, and unto each and every one who hold any dignity in them, now behold, he is like unto a god..."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_RUBAIYAT">
	        <Text>"The Moving Finger writes; and, having writ,[NEWLINE]Moves on; nor all thy piety nor wit[NEWLINE]Shall lure it back to cancel half a line,[NEWLINE]Nor all thy tears wash out a word of it."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_RUNESTONE">
	        <Text>"I say this the second, who nine generations ago lost his life with the Hreidgoths, and died with them for his guilt."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_SAUL">
	        <Text>"They shall record of thee, that David here[NEWLINE]Himself surrendered to ferocious Saul -[NEWLINE]March forth, O Israel, from thy peaceful tents;[NEWLINE]March forth from them, O King."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_SHINJUTEN_NO_AMIJIMA">
	        <Text>"To the ears of one possessed by the God of Death, reason and objections seem like so many idle complaints."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_SHUIHU_ZHUAN">
	        <Text>"Today our younger brother, Chen Da, went against our advice. He offended Your Excellency and has been locked within your honorable manor. Since we have no way to save him, we have come to die with him."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_FAERIE_QUEENE">
	        <Text>"For there is nothing lost, that may be found, if sought."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_GREAT_GATSBY">
	        <Text>"Gatsby believed in the green light, the orgastic future that year by year recedes before us. It eluded us then, but that's no matter - to-morrow we will run faster, stretch out our arms farther, and one fine morning..."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_LAST_OF_THE_MOHICANS">
	        <Text>"Chingachgook grasped the hand that, in the warmth of feeling, the scout had stretched across the fresh earth, and in that attitude of friendship these intrepid woodsmen bowed their heads together, while scalding tears fell to their feet, watering the grave of Uncas like drops of falling rain."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_RAVEN">
	        <Text>"Open here I flung the shutter, when, with many a flirt and flutter,[NEWLINE]In there stepped a stately raven of the saintly days of yore.[NEWLINE]Not the least obeisance made he; not a moment stopped or stayed he;[NEWLINE]But, with mien of lord or lady, perched above my chamber door."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_SIGN_OF_THE_FOUR">
	        <Text>"Once you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains, no matter how improbable, must be the truth."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_SKETCH_BOOK">
	        <Text>"And he would have passed a pleasant life of it, in despite of the Devil and all his works, if his path had not been crossed by a being that causes more perplexity to mortal man than ghosts, goblins, and the whole race of witches put together, and that was - a woman."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_THE_TIME_MACHINE">
	        <Text>"I think that at that time none of us quite believed in the Time Machine. The fact is, the Time Traveler was one of those men who are too clever to be believed: you never felt that you saw all around him; you always suspected some subtle reserve, some ingenuity in ambush, behind his lucid frankness."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_TRUE_STORY">
	        <Text>"I fall back on falsehood - but falsehood of a most consistent variety; for I now make the only true statement you are to expect - that I am a liar. This defense is, I consider, a full defense against all imputations."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_TSUREZUREGUSA">
	        <Text>"The most precious thing in life is its uncertainty. Leaving something incomplete makes it interesting and gives one the feeling that there is room for growth."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_TWICE_TOLD_TALE">
	        <Text>"Amid the seeming confusion of our mysterious world, individuals are so nicely adjusted to a system, and systems to one another and to a whole, that, by stepping aside for a moment, a man exposes himself to a fearful risk of losing his place forever."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_UGETSU_MONOGATARI">
	        <Text>"The moon glows on the river;[NEWLINE]Wind rustles the pine.[NEWLINE]Long night, clear evening -[NEWLINE]What are they for?"</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_UNCLE_TOMS_CABIN">
	        <Text>"Tom opened his eyes, and looked upon his master. 'Ye poor miserable critter!' he said, 'there ain't no more ye can do. I forgive ye, with all my soul!' and he fainted entirely away."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_URUBHANGA">
	        <Text>"The disease of suspicion is never in my being.[NEWLINE]For I am a king who can respect the friendship[NEWLINE]That flowers between a man and a woman."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_VIGNT_MILLE_LIEUES">
	        <Text>"Captain Nemo pointed to this prodigious heap of shellfish, and I saw that these mines were genuinely inexhaustible, since Nature's creative powers are greater than Man's destructive instincts."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_VOYNA_I_MIR">
	        <Text>"You can love a person dear to you with a human love, but an enemy can only be loved with divine love."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_WAGAHAI_WA_NEKO">
	        <Text>"Living as I do with human beings, the more that I observe them, the more I am forced to conclude that they are selfish."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_WALDEN">
	        <Text>"I went to the woods because I wished to live deliberately, to front only the essential facts of life, and see if I could not learn what it had to teach, and not, when I came to die, discover that I had not lived."</Text>
	    </Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_WONDERFUL_WIZARD_OF_OZ">
	        <Text>"'Oh - you're a very bad man!'[NEWLINE]'Oh no, my dear. I'm a very good man. I'm just a very bad Wizard.'"</Text>
	    </Row><!-- Muut kuin merkkiteosten lainaukset --><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BOROBUDUR_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kun huomaat kuinka täydellistä kaikki on, kippaat pääsi takakenoon ja naurat taivaalle."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Gautama Buddha[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BROADWAY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Broadway on New Yorkin kulttuurielämän ydin - kovettunut ydin."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Walter Winchell[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GLOBE_THEATER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Totus mundus agit histrionem"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Kaiverrus Globe-teatterin pääsisäänkäynnin yllä[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INTERNATIONAL_SPACE_STATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Vain yhden avaruusaseman rakentaminen meitä kaikkia varten oli ja on hullua; meidän olisi pitänyt rakentaa niitä tusina."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Larry Niven[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PARTHENON_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Maa ylväänä kantaa Parthenonia yhtenä rakkaimmista jalokivistään."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ralph Waldo Emerson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PRORA_RESORT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tämä (vapauden) menetys merkitsee kadotusta ihmiselämän arvoille, jotka ovat sille äärettömän arvokkaita. Jäljelle jää vain teräksin asetetut ehdot työllistymiselle ja vapaa-ajan tyhjänpäiväisille huvituksille."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - A.N. Whitehead[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RED_FORT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kun rakennamme, kuvitelkaamme rakentavamme ainiaan."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - John Ruskin[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_UFFIZI_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Taiteilija ei ole henkilö, joka vain katsoo ja näkee. Kaikkein olennaisimpana taiteilija on henkilö, joka paljastaa oman visionsa työstämällä sen nähtäväksi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Marcel Paquet[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_BALLOON_RECONNAISSANCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Olen saanut kunnian lähettää telegraafilla tämän ensimmäisen lähetyksen ilma-asemalta."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Thaddeus S. C. Lowe[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_CAVALRY_RAIDS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Jeb Stuart on ideaalini ratsuväen johtajaksi: täsmällinen, tarkka ja peloton."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Thomas J. Jackson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENGINEERING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Lakkaa pohtimasta mitä Bobby Lee aikoo tehdä meille, ja keskity siihen, mitä me tulemme tekemään hänelle."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ulysses S. Grant[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENTRENCHMENT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Olen aina katunut sitä, että viimeinen rynnäkkö Cold Harboriin tuli ylipäätään tehdyksi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ulysses S. Grant[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_FIELD_HOSPITALS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tämä konflikti on yksi asia, jota olen odottanut. Voin hyvin, olen vahva ja nuori - kyllin nuori mennäkseni rintamalle. Jos sotilaaksi en kelpaa, autan sotilaita."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Clara Barton[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_INDUSTRIALIZATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tämä vuosi on tuonut muassaan monia muutoksia, joita alussa olisi voinut pitää mahdottomuuksina."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Christian Fleetwood[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_IRONCLADS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tykkitornit ja muut osat aluksesta ottivat osumaa, mutta ammukset eivät päässeet lävitse; torni oli pystyssä ja jatkoi kuten ennenkin. Varmuus läpäisi miesten kasvot ja uskoimme, ettei Merrimac voisi toistaa eilisiä saavutuksiaan."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Samuel Dana Greene[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_RAILROADS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Pohjoinen kykenee rakentamaan höyrymoottorin, veturin ja junavaunun; te hyvä jos kykenette tekemään mytyn kangasta ja kenkäparin. Olette rynnimässä sotaan sellaista kansaa vastaan, joka on yksi voimakkaimmista, nerokkaan mekaanisimmista ja päättäväisimmistä - ja aivan ovenne edessä."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - William Tecumseh Sherman[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Miksi he kutsuvat näitä nimellä civil war (sisällissota), vaikka ne ovat kaikkea muuta kuin siviilejä?"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Elizabeth Fitch[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_REPEATING_RIFLES_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Parhaimmat upseerimme arvioivat, että yksi Spencer Carbinella varustettu mies vastaa kolmea minkä tahansa muun aseen kantajaa."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Major-General James H. Wilson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_RIFLED_ARTILLERY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Jenkkien kolmen tuuman rihlattu kanuuna kylvi kuoleman minne tahansa alle mailin matkalla. He kykenivät osumaan jauhotynnyrin päähän useammin kuin eivät, paitsi jos ampujaa häiritsi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Etelävaltioiden ampuja Atlantan taistelusta[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_SCORCHED_EARTH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Sota on helvettiä."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - William Tecumseh Sherman[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_10_QUOTE">
			<Text>Arvostelukyky tulee kokemuksesta, ja kokemus syntyy huonosta arvostelukyvystä.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_11_QUOTE">
			<Text>Hän joka laittaa kätensä eteen pysäyttääkseen historian pyörän tulee murskaamaan sormensa.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_12_QUOTE">
			<Text>Lisäksi katson olevani hyvässä ymmärryksessä valtiomme asioista, jatkuvista sodistamme vihamielisiä kansoja kohtaan, sekä köyhän kansani hyvinvoinnista.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_13_QUOTE">
			<Text>Herrani, ellei se tyydyttäisi maailmaa, tahi valtakuntaani, en tekisi tätä, minkä joudun tekemään, minkään maallisen asian vuoksi.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_14_QUOTE">
			<Text>Siunattuja ovat nuoret, sillä he perivät kansallisen velkamme.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_15_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kuuntelijat eivät koskaan kuule mitään hyvää itsestään.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_16_QUOTE">
			<Text>Sodassa, kutsui kumpi osapuoli tahansa itseään voittajaksi, ei ole voittajia, sillä kaikki häviävät.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_17_QUOTE">
			<Text>Ei ole nautintoa siinä, ettei tee mitään; hauskuus löytyy siitä, että on paljon tekemistä, eikä tee sitä.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_18_QUOTE">
			<Text>Niin merkittävä taiteilija, että kuolen!</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_19_QUOTE">
			<Text>Jossakin täytyy olla kirja, joka kertoo kaiken, jonka avulla voisin selvittää asiat omalle mielelleni. Mutta en tiedä missä kirja on, tahi osaisinko sitä lukea jos sen löytäisin.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_20_QUOTE">
			<Text>Okei, viisi minuuttia riittää, onko selvä?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_21_QUOTE">
			<Text>Törmäämme epäonnistumisen riskiin ellemme onnistu.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_2_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kun Marduk lähetti minut johtamaan ihmisiä antaen oikeuden suojella maata, toimin oikein ja oikeudenmukaisesti ja toin mukanani hyvinvoinnin sorretuille.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_3_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kanna aina mielessäsi, että oma päättäväisyytesi onnistua on tärkeämpi kuin mikään muu asia.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_4_QUOTE">
			<Text>Anna armeijani olla kivet ja puut, ja linnut taivaalla.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_5_QUOTE">
			<Text>Pessimisti näkee vaikeudet kaikissa mahdollisuuksissa; optimisti näkee mahdollisuudet kaikissa vaikeuksissa.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_6_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kaikki vaikuttaa mahdottomalta, kunnes se on tehty.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_7_QUOTE">
			<Text>Vaikka jokin asia vaikuttaa sinulle vaikealta, älä ajattele sen olevan mahdotonta jollakulla saavuttaa.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DQ_LEADER_NAME_9_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kohdatessaan kriisin luonteeltaan vahva mies nojaa itseensä. Hän määrää omat toimensa, ottaa niistä vastuun ja tekee tilanteesta omansa.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ERA_BALLISTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"'Kun raketit ovat ylhäällä, kuka välittää missä ne tulevat alas?[NEWLINE]        Se ei ole minun asiani,' sanoi Wernher von Braun."[NEWLINE]        [NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Tom Lehrer[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_ERA_PUBLISHING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Teoksen kirjoittamisessa on kolme hankalaa asiaa: julkaisun arvoisen kirjoituksen laatiminen, rehellisen miehen löytäminen sen julkaisemiseksi, ja löytää järkeviä lukijoita."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Charles Caleb Colton[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MEDIEVAL_SCENARIO_WONDER_UNITED_NATIONS_QUOTE">
			<Text>Kivikasa lakkaa olemasta kivikasa siinä vaiheessa kun yksi mies alkaa pohtia sitä ja näkee mielessään katedraalin.[NEWLINE] - Antoine de Saint-Exupery</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_IMPERIALISM_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Imperialismi on paperitiikeri."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Mao Zedong[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_NAVAL_TRADITION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Älä kerro minulle merenkäynnin perinteistä. Se ei ole muuta kuin rommia, sodomiaa ja ruoska."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Winston Churchill[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_PIRACY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ainoat säännöt joilla on väliä, ovat nämä: mitä mies voi tehdä, ja mitä mies voi olla tekemättä... voisin antaa teidän hukkua, mutta tätä laivaa ei voi saattaa Tortugaan yhden miehen voimin, ymmärrättehän? Joten valintanne on, voitteko purjehtia piraatin komennossa, vai ettekö voi?"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Kapteeni Jack Sparrow[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_PROSOLDIERS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Huolimatta sotilaan urastani en ole koskaan tuntenut sotaa mieluisaksi, en ole koskaan puhunut sen puolesta, paitsi ratkaisuna rauhan saamiseksi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ulysses S. Grant[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_RELIGIOUS_ORDERS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tuntemani jesuiitat, jotka ovat kuolleet ja olivat koko elämänsä mahtavia opettajia, ovat vähiten muistettuja ihmisiä."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Daniel Berrigan[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_ROYAL_GUARDS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tämä maailma on epävarmuuden sijaa, täynnä vaaroja. Kunnia jonka vallanhimo on tyrehdyttänyt, vapaus joka uhrataan kun vahvat sortavat heikkoja. On kuitenkin olemassa heitä, jotka käyvät näitä vahvoja voimia vastaan, jotka omistavat elämänsä totuudelle, kunnialle ja vapaudelle. Nämä miehet ovat musketöörejä. Nouskaat"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Kuningas Ludvig[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_TREASURE_FLEET_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kulta on aarre, ja hän joka omistaa sen tekee kaiken haluamansa tässä maailmassa ja onnistuu auttaessaan sieluja paratiisiin."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Christopher Columbus[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_TECH_WARSHIPS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Himskatin torpedot, täyttä häkää eteenpäin!"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Amiraali David Glasgow Farragut[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_TECH_AQUACULTURE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Vesiviljely on riskikästä toimintaa. Siihen ei voi ryhtyä rahan vuoksi. Sitä tehdään rakkauden tähden."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Michael Matthews[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_TECH_CEREMONIAL_DANCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Uskoisin ainoastaan Jumalaan, joka tietää kuinka Tanssia."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Friedrich Nietzsche[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_TECH_ORNAMENTAL_CARVING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Näin enkelin marmorissa, ja kaiversin kunnes hän oli vapaa."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Michelangelo[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_TECH_TATTOO_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mies ilman tatuointeja on näkymätön jumalille."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Iban Proverb[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_TECH_WAYFINDING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Airo tummansinisen meremme iloisia vesiä, aatoksemme rajattomina ja sielumme vapaana, kaukana minne tuulahdus viedä voi, missä aallot vaahtoutuvat; tutki valtakuntamme ja koe kotimme! "[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Lordi Byron[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALOG_COMPUTATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Laskettavaa on aina riittämiin miljoonien ihmisten tehdessä monimutkaisia asioita."[NEWLINE] - Vannevar Bush[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Aritmetiikka kaikkinensa on nyt mekaniikan otteessa."[NEWLINE] - Charles Babbage[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_AUTOMATA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Sivilisaatio edistyy kasvattamalla niiden tärkeiden suoritettavien asioiden määrää - vapautuen niiden ajattelusta."[NEWLINE] - Alfred North Whitehead[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_CIVIL_DEFENSE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Puolustus on ylellisyyksiä tähdellisempää."[NEWLINE] - Adam Smith[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ECONOMIC_IMPERIALISM_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ahneus, teollisuuden kannustin."[NEWLINE] - David Hume[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ERUPTIVES_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Luonto, jota hallita, tulee totella."[NEWLINE] - Francis Bacon[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_EXPEDITIONARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Korvessa tunnen elämän ihmeen ja siihen nähden tieteelliset saavutuksemme kalpenevat turhuutena."[NEWLINE] - Charles Lindbergh[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_GOSPEL_OF_WEALTH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Päädyin lakkaamaan kahmimasta yhä enemmän, ja aloitin loputtomasti vakavamman ja hankalamman tehtävän jakaa viisaasti."[NEWLINE] - Andrew Carnegie[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_INFERNAL_COMBUSTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Todellisin kaikista näkyvistä mysteereistä - tuli."[NEWLINE] - James Henry Leigh Hunt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LANDSHIPS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Puolustajat oli ajattu oikealle ja vasemmalle välittömästi kun tämän maapanssarin keula ilmaantui juoksuhaudan edustalle."[NEWLINE] - H.G. Wells[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LAND_LEVIATHAN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Puhu pehmeästi ja kanna isoa keppiä; pääset pitkälle."[NEWLINE] - Theodore Roosevelt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_NOBLESSE_OBLIGE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Hyveet ovat todellisinta jaloutta."[NEWLINE] - Miguel de Cervantes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PERPETUAL_MOTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Anna minulle paikka seistä ja tarpeeksi pitkä vipuvarsi, ja liikutan maailmaa."[NEWLINE] - Archimedes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PROPULSION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Lentokoneen keksiminen on merkityksetöntä. Lentokoneen rakentaminen on jo jotakin. Mutta lentäminen... se on olennaisinta."[NEWLINE] - Ferdinand Ferber[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SKY_FORTRESS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mikä tahansa riittävän kehittynyt teknologia on mahdotonta erottaa taikuudesta."[NEWLINE] - Arthur C. Clarke[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SUBTERRANEAN_EXPLORATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Yksi oikeutettu periaate luolien syvyyksistä on voimakkaampi kuin armeija."[NEWLINE] - José Martí[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_TECHNOCRACY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Järjen hallitus on parempi kuin voimaan perustuva."[NEWLINE] - Thomas Jefferson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_THE_GRAND_IDEA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ihmiset rakastavat ihmetellä ja se on tieteemme siemen."[NEWLINE] - Ralph Waldo Emerson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_URANOGRAPHY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Lennän, sillä se vapauttaa mieleni mitättömien asioiden tyrannialta."[NEWLINE] - Antoine de Saint Exupéry[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_VERTICAL_INTEGRATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kilpailu on synti."[NEWLINE] - John D. Rockefeller[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ACOUSTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Heidän kaikkien nousu kerralla seisomaan oli kuin kaukaa kuultu ukkosmyrsky."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Milton</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ADVANCED_BALLISTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tieteellinen mahtimme on ylittänyt henkisen voimamme. Meillä on hakeutuvia ohjuksia ja harhautettuja miehiä."[NEWLINE] - Martin Luther King, Jr.[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_AGRICULTURE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mistä viljely alkaa, sitä muut taidot seuraavat. Viljelijät ovat siten ihmisten sivilisaation perustajia."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Daniel Webster[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ANIMAL_HUSBANDRY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Älkää sitoko puivan härän suuta."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Raamattu, Viides Mooseksen kirja, 25:4[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHAEOLOGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tuomittuja toistamaan menneen ovat he, jotka eivät sitä muista."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - George Santayana[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHERY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Nuolen varsi oli varustettu yhdellä kotkan omista höyhenistä. Annamme usein vihollisillemme keinot omaan tuhoomme."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Aesop[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ARCHITECTURE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Arkkitehtuuri alkaa siitä, mihin insinööritaito päättyy."[NEWLINE] - Walter Gropius[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ASTRONOMY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Iloissaan ruhtinas Ulysses levitti purjeensa tuulen henkäykseen ja ohjasti taiten peräsimellään."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Homer[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ATOMIC_THEORY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Atomin valjastettu poma on muuttanut kaiken paitsi ajattelumme tason ja näinpä ajaudumme kohti ennennäkemättömiä katastrofeja."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Albert Einstein[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_BALLISTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Miehet, aivan kuten luodit, pääsevät pisimmälle ollessaan sutjakoita."[NEWLINE] - Jean Paul[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_BANKING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Onnellisuus: hyvä tili pankissa, hyvä kokki ja hyvää luettavaa."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Jean Jacques Rousseau[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_BIOLOGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Jos aivot olisivat niin yksinkertaiset, että ymmärtäisimme niitä, olisimme niin yksinkertaisia, ettemme kykenisi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Lyall Watson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_BRONZE_WORKING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Sinne Hector astui kädessään yhdentoista kyynärän keihäs; pronssikärki säteili hänen edessään ollen kiinnitettynä keihään varteen kultareunuksin."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Homer[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CALCULUS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Syksyllä 1972 presidentti Nixon ilmoitti inflaation kasvun laskeneen. Tämä oli ensimmäinen kerta, kun istuva presidentti käytti kolmatta derivaattaa edistääkseen mahdollisuuksiaan uudelleenvalintaan."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Hugo Rossi[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CALENDAR_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Opeta meitä laskemaan päivämme oikein, että me saisimme viisaan sydämen."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Raamattu, Psalmsit, 90:12[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CHEMISTRY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Minne vain katsommekin, on kemistin työ nostanut sivilisaatiomme tasoa ja kasvattanut kansamme tuotantokapasiteettia."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Calvin Coolidge[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CHIVALRY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ken vetääkään tämän miekan tästä kivestä ja alasimesta on oikeutetusti syntynyt koko Englannin kuninkaaksi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Malory[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CIVIL_SERVICE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ainoa byrokratialta pelastava asia on sen tehottomuus."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Eugene McCarthy[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBINED_ARMS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Pahuuden lähde ei ole uusien pelottavampien aseiden valmistus, vaan valloittamisen henki."[NEWLINE] - Ludwig von Mises[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_COMBUSTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mies joka voi ajaa turvallisesti suudellessaan kaunista tyttöä ei anna suudelmalle sitä huomiota, jonka se ansaitsisi."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Albert Einstein[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPASS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mahtava asia tässä maailmassa ei ole se missä olemme, vaan se, mihin suuntaan olemme menossa..."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Oliver Wendell Holmes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_COMPUTERS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Tietokoneet ovat kuten vanhan testamentin jumalat: paljon sääntöjä eikä tippaakaan armoa."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Joseph Campbell[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CONSTRUCTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kolmea asiaa ovat merkittäviä rakennukselle: jotta se on oikealla sijalla; jotta se on perustettu turvallisesti; jotta se on rakennettu onnistuneesti."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Johann Wolfgang von Goethe[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_CURRENCY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Parempi on leipä iloiselle sydämelle[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  Kuin vauraus ärtyneelle."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Amenemope[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_DRAMA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mitä onkaan draama kuin elämää ilman tylsiä osuuksia."[NEWLINE] - Alfred Hitchcock[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_DYNAMITE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Siinä vaiheessa kun päätetään, että kaikki keinot ovat sallittuja taistossa pahaa vastaan, tulee hyvistä aikeista mahdotonta erottaa siitä pahasta, joka oli tarkoitus tuhota."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Christopher Dawson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ECOLOGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ajan silmänräpäyksessä eli tämän vuosisadan aikana on yksi laji, ihminen, ottanut haltuunsa suuren vallan kyvyllään muokata tämän maailman luontoa."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Rachel Carson[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ECONOMICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Kertyvä korko on universumin tehokkain voima."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Albert Einstein[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_EDUCATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Koulutus on paras turva vanhuuteen."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Aristotle[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRICITY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Is it a fact - or have I dreamt it - that, by means of electricity, the world of matter has become a great nerve, vibrating thousands of miles in a breathless point of time?"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Nathaniel Hawthorne[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ELECTRONICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There's a basic principle about consumer electronics: it gets more powerful all the time and it gets cheaper all the time."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Trip Hawkins[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ENGINEERING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Instrumental or mechanical science is the noblest and, above all others, the most useful."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Leonardo da Vinci[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_EXPLORATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"We shall not cease from exploration, and the end of all our exploring will be to arrive where we started and know the place for the first time."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - T. S. Eliot[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_FERTILIZER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The nation that destroys its soil destroys itself."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_FLIGHT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Aeronautics was neither an industry nor a science. It was a miracle."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Igor Sikorsky[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_GLOBALIZATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The new electronic interdependence recreates the world in the image of a global village."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Marshall McLuhan[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_GUILDS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The merchants and the traders have come; their profits are pre-ordained..."[NEWLINE] - Sri Guru Granth Sahib[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_GUNPOWDER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The day when two army corps can annihilate each other in one second, all civilized nations, it is to be hoped, will recoil from war and discharge their troops."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Alfred Nobel[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_HORSEBACK_RIDING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"My kingdom for a horse!"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Shakespeare (Richard III)[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_HUMANISM_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Give light, and the darkness will disappear of itself."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Desiderius Erasmus [NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_INDUSTRIALIZATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Industrialization based on machinery, already referred to as a characteristic of our age, is but one aspect of the revolution that is being wrought by technology."[NEWLINE] - Emily Greene Balch[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_INTERNET_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The Internet is the first thing that humanity has built that humanity doesn't understand, the largest experiment in anarchy that we have ever had."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Eric Schmidt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_IRON_WORKING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Do not wait to strike 'til the iron is hot; but make it hot by striking."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - William Butler Yeats[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_LASERS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The night is far spent, the day is at hand: let us therefore cast off the works of darkness, and let us put on the armor of light."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - The Holy Bible: Romans, 13:12 [NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MACHINERY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The press is the best instrument for enlightening the mind of man, and improving him as a rational, moral and social being."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Thomas Jefferson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MASONRY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"How happy are those whose walls already rise!"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Virgil[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MASS_MEDIA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The speed of communications is wondrous to behold. It is also true that speed can multiply the distribution of information that we know to be untrue."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Edward R. Murrow[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MATHEMATICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Mathematics is the gate and key to the sciences."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Roger Bacon[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_METALLURGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There never was a good knife made of bad steel."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Benjamin Franklin[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_METAL_CASTING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"When pieces of bronze or gold or iron break, the metal-smith welds them together again in the fire, and the bond is established."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Sri Guru Granth Sahib[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Wars may be fought with weapons, but they are won by men. It is the spirit of the men who follow and of the man who leads that gains the victory."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - George S. Patton[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MINING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The meek shall inherit the Earth, but not its mineral rights."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - J. Paul Getty[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_MOBILE_TACTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"All men can see these tactics whereby I conquer, but what none can see is the strategy out of which victory is evolved."[NEWLINE] - Sun Tzu[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_NANOTECHNOLOGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The impact of nanotechnology is expected to exceed the impact that the electronics revolution has had on our lives."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Richard Schwartz[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVIGATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The winds and the waves are always on the side of the ablest navigators."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Edward Gibbon[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_NUCLEAR_FISSION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - J. Robert Oppenheimer[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_NUCLEAR_FUSION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The release of atomic energy has not created a new problem. It has merely made more urgent the necessity of solving an existing one."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Albert Einstein[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_OPTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"He made an instrument to know[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  If the moon shine at full or no."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Samuel Butler[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PARTICLE_PHYSICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Every particle of matter is attracted by or gravitates to every other particle of matter with a force inversely proportional to the squares of their distances."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Isaac Newton[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PATRONAGE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Everything passes - Robust art[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  Alone is eternal.[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  The bust[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  Survives the city."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Theophile Gautier[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PENICILIN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"In nothing do men more nearly approach the gods than in giving health to men."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Cicero[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PHILOSOPHY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Socrates[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PHYSICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Measure what is measurable, and make measurable what is not so."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Galileo[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PLASTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Ben, I want to say one word to you, just one word: plastics."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Buck Henry and Calder Willingham, The Graduate[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_POTTERY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Shall the clay say to him that fashioneth it, What makest thou?"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - The Bible, Isaiah, 45:9[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_PRINTING_PRESS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"It is a newspaper's duty to print the news and raise hell."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - The Chicago Times[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_RADAR_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Vision is the art of seeing things invisible."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Jonathan Swift[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_RADIO_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The whole country was tied together by radio. We all experienced the same heroes and comedians and singers. They were giants."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Woody Allen[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_RAILROAD_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The introduction of so powerful an agent as steam to a carriage on wheels will make a great change in the situation of man."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Thomas Jefferson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_REFRIGERATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"And homeless near a thousand homes I stood, and near a thousand tables pined and wanted food."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - William Wordsworth[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Nothing is particularly hard if you divide it into small jobs."[NEWLINE][TAB]  - Henry Ford[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_RIFLING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"It is well that war is so terrible, or we should grow too fond of it."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Robert E. Lee[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ROBOTICS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"1. A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]2. A robot must obey any orders given to it by human beings, except when such orders would conflict with the First Law.[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]3. A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict with the First or Second Law."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Isaac Asimov[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_ROCKETRY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"A good rule for rocket experimenters to follow is this: always assume that it will explode."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Astronautics Magazine, 1937[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_SAILING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"He who commands the sea has command of everything."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Themistocles[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_SATELLITES_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Now, somehow, in some new way, the sky seemed almost alien."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Lyndon B. Johnson[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_SCIENTIFIC_THEORY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Every great advance in science has issued from a new audacity of imagination."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - John Dewey[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_STEALTH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Be extremely subtle, even to the point of formlessness.  Be extremely mysterious, even to the point of soundlessness.  Thereby you can be the director of the opponent's fate."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Sun Tzu[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_STEAM_POWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The nations of the West hope that by means of steam communication all the world will become as one family."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Townsend Harris[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_STEEL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"John Henry said to his Captain,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]'A man ain't nothin' but a man,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  And before I'll let your steam drill beat me down,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  I'll die with the hammer in my hand.'"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Anonymous: The Ballad of John Henry, the Steel-Drivin' Man[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_TELECOM_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The more we elaborate our means of communication, the less we communicate."[NEWLINE] - J.B. Priestly[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_TELEGRAPH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I once sent a dozen of my friends a telegram saying 'flee at once - all is discovered.' They all left town immediately."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Mark Twain[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_THEOLOGY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Three things are necessary for the salvation of man: to know what he ought to believe; to know what he ought to desire; and to know what he ought to do."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - St. Thomas Aquinas[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_THE_WHEEL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Wisdom and virtue are like the two wheels of a cart."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - Japanese Proverb[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_TRAPPING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Even brute beasts and wandering birds do not fall into the same traps or nets twice."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Saint Jerome[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TECH_WRITING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"He who destroys a good book kills reason itself."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]  - John Milton[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_ALHAMBRA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Justice is an unassailable fortress, built on the brow of a mountain which cannot be overthrown by the violence of torrents, nor demolished by the force of armies."[NEWLINE]- Joseph Addison[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_ANGKORWAT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The temple is like no other building in the world. It has towers and decoration and all the refinements which the human genius can conceive of."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Antonio da Magdalena[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BIGBEN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"To achieve great things, two things are needed: a plan, and not quite enough time."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Leonard Bernstein[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BRANDENBURGGATE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Pale Death beats equally at the poor man's gate and at the palaces of kings."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Horace[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CHICHENITZA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The katun is established at Chichen Itza. The settlement of the Itza shall take place there. The quetzal shall come, the green bird shall come. Ah Kantenal shall come. It is the word of God. The Itza shall come."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Books of Chilam Balam[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CN_TOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Nothing travels faster than the speed of light with the possible exception of bad news, which obeys its own special laws."[NEWLINE]- Douglas Adams[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_COLOSSUS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Why man, he doth bestride the narrow world like a colossus; and we petty men walk under his huge legs, and peep about to find ourselves dishonorable graves."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - William Shakespeare: Julius Caesar[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CRISTOREDENTOR_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Come to me, all who labor and are heavy burdened, and I will give you rest."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Bible, Matthew 25:28[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_EIFFELTOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"We live only to discover beauty. All else is a form of waiting."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Kahlil Gibran[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_FORBIDDENPALACE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Most of us can, as we choose, make of this world either a palace or a prison."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - John Lubbock[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_GREATLIBRARY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Libraries are as the shrine where all the relics of the ancient saints, full of true virtue, and all that without delusion or imposture are preserved and reposed."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Sir Francis Bacon[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_GREATLIGHTHOUSE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"They that go down to the sea in ships, that do business in great waters; these see the works of the Lord, and his wonders in the deep."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Bible, Psalms 107:23-24[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_GREATWALL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The art of war teaches us to rely not on the likelihood of the enemy's... not attacking, but rather on the fact that we have made our position unassailable."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Sun Tzu[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_GREAT_FIREWALL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Distrust and caution are the parents of security."[NEWLINE]- Benjamin Franklin[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_HAGIASOPHIA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"For it soars to a height to match the sky, and as if surging up from amongst the other buildings it stands on high and looks down upon the remainder of the city, adorning it, because it is a part of it, but glorying in its own beauty."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Procopius, De Aedificis[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_HANGINGGARDENS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I think that if ever a mortal heard the word of God it would be in a garden at the cool of the day."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - F. Frankfort Moore[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_HIMEJICASTLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Bushido is realized in the presence of death. This means choosing death whenever there is a choice between life and death. There is no other reasoning."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Yamamoto Tsunetomo[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_HUBBLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The wonder is, not that the field of stars is so vast, but that man has measured it."[NEWLINE]- Anatole France[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_KREMLIN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The Law is a fortress on a hill that armies cannot take or floods wash away."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Prophet Muhammed[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LEANING_TOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Don't clap too hard - it's a very old building."[NEWLINE]- John Osborne[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_LOUVRE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Every genuine work of art has as much reason for being as the earth and the sun."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ralph Waldo Emerson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_MACHUPICCHU_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Few romances can ever surpass that of the granite citadel on top of the beetling precipices of Machu Picchu, the crown of Inca Land."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Hiram Bingham[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_MOSQUE_OF_DJENNE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"With the magnificence of eternity before us, let time, with all its fluctuations, dwindle into its own littleness."[NEWLINE]- Thomas Chalmers[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_NEUSCHWANSTEIN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"...the location is one of the most beautiful to be found, holy and unapproachable, a worthy temple for the divine friend who has brought salvation and true blessing to the world."[NEWLINE]- King Ludwig II of Bavaria[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_NOTREDAME_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Architecture has recorded the great ideas of the human race. Not only every religious symbol, but every human thought has its page in that vast book."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Victor Hugo[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_ORACLE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The ancient Oracle said that I was the wisest of all the Greeks. It is because I alone, of all the Greeks, know that I know nothing."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Socrates[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_PENTAGON_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"In preparing for battle I have always found that plans are useless, but planning is indispensible."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Dwight D. Eisenhower[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_PETRA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"...who drinks the water I shall give him, says the Lord, will have a spring inside him welling up for eternal life. Let them bring me to your holy mountain in the place where you dwell. Across the desert and through the mountain to the Canyon of the Crescent Moon..."[NEWLINE]- Indiana Jones[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_PORCELAINTOWER_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Things always seem fairer when we look back at them, and it is out of that inaccessible tower of the past that Longing leans and beckons."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - James Russell Lowell[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_PYRAMIDS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"O, let not the pains of death which come upon thee enter into my body. I am the god Tem, and I am in the foremost part of the sky, and the power which protecteth me is that which is with all the gods forever."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Book of the Dead, translated by Sir Ernest Alfred Wallis Budge[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SISTINECHAPEL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I live and love in God's peculiar light."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Michelangelo Buonarroti[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_STATUEOFLIBERTY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Give me your tired, your poor,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]The wretched refuse of your teeming shore.[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]Send these, the homeless, tempest-tossed to me,[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]I lift my lamp beside the golden door!"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Emma Lazarus[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_STATUE_ZEUS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"He spoke, the son of Kronos, and nodded his head with the dark brows, and the immortally anointed hair of the great god swept from his divine head, and all Olympos was shaken."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - The Iliad[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_STONEHENGE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Time crumbles things; everything grows old and is forgotten under the power of time."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Aristotle[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SYDNEY_OPERA_HOUSE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Those who lose dreaming are lost."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Australian Aboriginal saying[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_TAJMAHAL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The Taj Mahal rises above the banks of the river like a solitary tear suspended on the cheek of time."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Rabindranath Tagore[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_TERRACOTTA_ARMY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Regard your soldiers as your children, and they will follow you into the deepest valleys; look on them as your own beloved sons, and they will stand by you even unto death."[NEWLINE]- Sun Tzu[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_UNITEDNATIONS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"More than ever before in human history, we share a common destiny. We can master it only if we face it together. And that is why we have the United Nations."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Kofi Annan[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_fi_FI>
</GameData>