<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<Language_fi_FI>
	
	<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ARABIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Jumalten siunausta teille, oi suuri kalifi Harun al-Rashid, hurskaan Arabian kansan johtaja! Kalifaatin muslimivaltakunta syntyi vuonna 632 tapahtuneen profeetta Muhammadin kuoleman jälkeisinä myrskyisinä vuosina, kun hänen seuraajansa pyrkivät laajentamaan Jumalan vallan kaikille maailman kansoille. Kalifaatti todellakin kasvoi mahtavaksi, sillä voimansa päivinä se hallitsi Espanjaa, Pohjois-Afrikkaa, Lähi-itää, Anatoliaa, Balkania ja Persiaa, ollen yhtä mahtava - ellei mahtavampi - kuin Rooma. Taiteet ja tieteet kukoistivat Arabiassa keskiajalla, vaikka Euroopassa maat ajautuivat kaaokseen ja tietämättömyyteen. Kalifaatti säilyi 600 vuotta aina mongolien vyöryyn asti.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Suuri kalifi Harun al-Rashid, kansanne katsoo teihin ja toivoo teidän palauttavan heidät kukoistukseen. Kukoistukseen täynnä taidetta ja tietoutta, täyteen vahvuutta jotta vihollisia ei tarvitse peljätä. Oi kalifi, onko teistä tähän haasteeseen? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ARABIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Arabia</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_AZTECS_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdys, oi pyhä Montezuma! Ryömimme ihmeissämme uskomattomuutenne edessä! Kylväköön taivaat yllenne kaikkea hyvää kaikki elämänne päivät! Olette suurten asteekkien johtaja, vaeltavien paimenten herra, jotka menettivät kotinsa pohjoisessa 1100-luvulla ja siirtyivät keskiseen Mesaan alueelle, jota myöhemmin alettiin kutsua Meksikoksi. Useiden keskenään taistelevien heimojen joukosta asteekit nousivat Texcocon, Xaltocanin ja Zumpangon järviä ympäröivien rikkaiden maiden valtiaiksi. Kiitoksena ovelista liittolaisuuksista ja taistelutaidoista asteekit hallitsivat keskistä Amerikkaa mereltä toiselle. Valtakunta hajosi viimein ulkoisten pirujen - kirottuja olkoon espanjalaiset! - toimesta, jotka käyttivät aseita, joita sotilaanne eivät olleet kuunaan nähneet.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi suuri kuningas Montezuma! Kansanne kutsuu teitä nousemaan jälleen ja johtamaan heidät kunniaan! Tarjoa heille rikkauksia ja voimaa, anna heille valta yli kilpailijoiden ja vihollisten! Mahtava johtaja, kykenettekö vastaamaan heidän kutsuunsa? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_AZTECS_TITLE">
			<Text>Asteekit</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_BABYLON_TEXT">
			<Text>Siunatkoon taivas teitä, oi suuri Nebukadressar, muinaisen ja mahtavan Babylonian isä! Maailma oli nuori Sargonin rakentaessa Babylonin viisi tuhatta vuotta sitten. Pitkään se kasvoi ja kukoisti, kasvaen ensimmäiseksi valtakunnaksi 1700-luvulla eaa. jumalaisen lait antaneen Hammurabin alaisuudessa. Vaikka kassiitit ja sittemmin assyrialaiset valloittivat Babylonian, se kuitenkin kesti höykytyksen ja nousi feenikslinnun lailla tuhon tuhkista ja palautti itsenäisyytensä lukuisista vihollisistaan huolimatta. Babylonia todellakin oli muinaisen maailman taiteen ja oppimisen keskus![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi Nebukadressar, valtakuntanne kesti vain lyhyen aikaa kuolemanne jälkeen, kaatuen mahtavien persialaisten ja myöhemmin kreikkalaisten ikeen alle, kunnes Babylonin kaupunki oli tuhotti 141 eaa. mennessä. Vaan onko Babylonia kadonnut ainiaaksi, suuri Nebukadressar? Kansanne luottaa teidän tuovan valtakunnan takaisin vielä kerran! Otatteko haasteen vastaan? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_BABYLON_TITLE">
			<Text>Babylonia</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_CHINA_TEXT">
			<Text>Taivaan siunaukset olkoon yllänne valtiatar Wu Zetian, kaunein ja koppavin Kiinan hallitsija! Oi suuri valtiatar, jonka varjo saa kukat kukkimaan ja joet virtaamaan! Olette ihmiskunnan sivilisaatioista vanhimpien ja mahtavimpien - kiinalaisten - johtaja. Kiinan tarina kulkee kauas historian hämäriin ja sen kansa saavutti monia suuria asioita ennen kuin vähäisemmät sivilisaatiot olivat edes saaneet alkuaan. Kiinan ensinluomat taiteet ja tieteet ovat niin lukuisat, ettei niille voi tehdä oikeutta - kirjapaino, ruuti, Kungfutsen työt - nämä ovat vain vähän siitä, mitä Kiina on antanut muulle maailmalle![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Te, suuri kuningatar, olette oveluudellanne ja kauneudellanne nousseet vähäisen jalkavaimon asemasta pyhäksi keisarinnaksi - siis kuulkaa kansanne kutsu, hallitkaa heitä! Suuri Kiina on jälleen barbaarien ympäröimä. Kykenettekö lyömään lukuiset vastustajanne ja palauttamaan valtakuntanne mahdin? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_CHINA_TITLE">
			<Text>Kiina</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_DENMARK_TEXT">
			<Text>Ylistys ja kunnia kanssanne, Harald Sinihammas Gorminpoika, Gorm Vanhan ja Thyre Danebodin perijä. Ette olleet ainoastaan voittoisia Norjan armeijoita vastaan, vaan suorititte suuria rakennusprojekteja ympäri maitanne - rakennutitte lukuisia kehälinnoituksia suojellaksenne kansaanne valloituksilta ja sisäisiltä selkkauksilta. Ajoitte tiehensä saksalaisten uudisasuttajien laumat 983 jaa. ja suojasitte kuningaskuntanne ulkovaltojen vaikutukselta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Vanttera viikinki, on tullut jälleen aika suuruuden. Olette saaneet kutsun nousta ja johtaa kansanne valtaan ja kunniaan! Saatteko jälleen maailman vapisemaan ajatuksestakin pohjoisten miestenne armeijoista? Annatteko viikinkien taisteluhuutojen kuulua aaltojen kuohunnan ylitse? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_EGYPT_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdimme teitä, oi suuri Ramses, Egyptin faarao! Saatte auringon nousemaan ja Niilin virtaamaan, sekä siunaatte onnekasta kansaanne kaikella, mikä on hyvää elämässä! Oi suuri herra, kansanne on elänyt jo iäisyyden Niilin rannoilla, jossa he toivat maailmaan kirjoitustaidon, kehittyneen matematiikan, kuvanveiston ja arkkitehtuurin. Tuhansia vuosia sitten he rakensivat suuret monumentit, jotka edelleen seisovat korkeina ja ylväinä.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi Ramses, lukemattomat vuodet on kansanne kestänyt, kun toiset vähäisemmät kansat ovat nousseet ja taas kaatuneet unohdukseen. Kansanne odottaa teidän vievän heidät uuteen kukoistukseen. Kykenettekö kunnioittamaan jumalia ja tuomaan Egyptin takaisin oikeutetulle paikalleen maailman keskuksessa? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_EGYPT_TITLE">
			<Text>Egypti</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ENGLAND_TEXT">
			<Text>Rukoukset yllänne teidän seesteinen korkeutenne, kuningatar Elisabet Gloriana, ylvään mertakäyvän Englannin johtaja ja suojelija. Englanti on muinainen maa. Se asutettiin jo 35 000 vuotta sitten ja maa on kokenut lukemattomien valtaajien aallot, kukin jättäen jälkensä väestön koostumukseen. Vaikka Englanti on pieni saari, kykeni sen kansa monien vuosien ajan hallitsemaan maailmaa niin loistavan laivastonsa, erinomaisten taiteilijoidensa kuin ovelien kauppiaidensa ansiosta, kasvattaen heidän valtansa ja vaikutuksensa laajemmalle kuin pelkästä väkiluvusta voisi päätellä.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kuningatar Elisabet, tuotteko uuden kultaisen kauden Englannin kansalle? He toivovat teidän tuovan maalleen rauhaa ja vaurautta jälleen kerran. Puetteko itsenne suuruuteen? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ENGLAND_TITLE">
			<Text>Englanti</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_FRANCE_TEXT">
			<Text>Pitkää ikää ja kunniaa teille, Ranskan ensimmäinen konsuli ja keisari Napoleon I, ranskalaisten hallitsija. Ranska sijaitsee Euroopan sydämessä. Pariisi on pitkään ollut maailman keskus kulttuurille, taiteille ja kirjeille. Huolimatta sijainnistaan keskellä kilpailijoita - ja vihollisia - on Ranska kestänyt suurena valtakuntana. Sen armeijat ovat kulkeneet kunniakkaasti taistelusta toiseen maailman ääreltä toiselle ja sen sotilaat ja kenraalit lukeutuvat historian parhaimpien joukkoon.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Napoleon Bonaparte, Ranska kaipaa teidän kättänne valtakuntansa uudelleenrakennukseen, johtamaan heidät uuteen kunniaan ja kukoistukseen, jotta Ranska olisi jälleen kulttuurin ja hienostuneisuuden ilmentymä. Keisari, voitteko ratsastaa vielä kerran vihollisianne vastaan? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_FRANCE_TITLE">
			<Text>Ranska</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GERMANY_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdys teille Bismarck, Saksan ensimmäinen valtakunnankansleri! Saksa on tuore valtakunta, joka syntyi Pyhän saksalais-roomalaisen keisarikunnan raunioista, yhdentyen viimein vuonna 1871 eli vain hieman reilu vuosisata sitten. Saksalaiset ovat osoittaneet olevansa luovia, tehokkaan aikaansaavia, sekä raivokkaita sotureja. 1900-luvun ensimmäisen puolikkaan katastrofista huolimatta Saksa on säilynyt maailmanlaajuisena talouden, taiteen ja teknologian johtajana.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Rakastettu rautakansleri Otto von Bismarck, Saksan kansa toivoo teidän tuovan heille uudet kunnian päivät. Heidän tahtonsa on luja ja he kääntyvät jälleen kerran teidän puoleenne. Johdatteko ja valtaatteko raudalla ja verellä, vai vaalitteko saksalaista taidetta ja teollisuutta? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GERMANY_TITLE">
			<Text>Saksa</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GREECE_TEXT">
			<Text>Olkoon jumalten siunaus yllänne, oi kuningas Aleksanteri Suuri! Olette mahtavan Kreikan valtakunnan hallitsija. Kansanne eli pitkään lukuisissa kaupunkivaltioissa - legendaarisissa kaupungeissa kuten Ateena, Sparta ja Theba - joissa he toivat maailmalle monia suuria asioita, kuten demokratian, filosofian, tragedian, taiteen ja arkkitehtuurin, länsimaisen sivistyksen pohjat. Huolimatta kansansa vähäisemmästä lukumäärästä ja keskinäisestä kinastelusta, pystyi teidän kansanne nousemaan kooltaan paljon suurempaa Persiaa vastaan 400-luvulla eaa. ja voittamaan heidät niin maalla kuin merellä.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Aleksanteri, kansanne on valmis marssimaan sotaan, leivttämään kreikkalaista kulttuuria miljoonille ja tarjoamaan teille iänkaikkisen kunnian. Oletteko valmis kohtaloonne, kuningas Aleksanteri? Johdatatteko kansanne kunniaan ja suuruuteen? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GREECE_TITLE">
			<Text>Kreikka</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_INCA_TEXT">
			<Text>Hän joka tekee maailman uudelleen, uskolliset alaimaisenne tervehtivät teitä, kuningas Pachacutec! Hallitsette inkoja. Inkat osoittivat potentiaalinsa suuruuteen aloittaen pienestä Cuscon valtiosta, marssien sotaan lukuisia vihollisiaan vastaan ja murskaten heidän armeijansa, luoden tällä tavalla mahtavan valtakunnan Equadorista Chileen. He todellakin rakensivat suurimman valtakunnan Kolumbusta edeltäneeseen Amerikkaan. Kansaanne ei tunnettu vain sotureistaan, vaan he olivat myös suuria rakentajia ja taiteilijoita, joiden kädenjälki aiheuttaa ihmetystä yhä nykyään.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi kuningas Pachacutec, te todellakin olette "Maanjäristäjä"! Kutsutteko jälleen maan itsensä taistelemaan puolellanne? Armeijanne odottavat käskyänne. Palautatteko valtakuntanne loistokkuuden? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_INCA_TITLE">
			<Text>Inkat</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_INDIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdys, presidentti Gandhi, Intian suurisieluinen johtaja! Olette vanhimpiin lukeutuvan valtion hallitsija, jonka historia ylettää liki 10 000 vuoden taakse! Henkisenä maana Intia on kolmen maailman suuren uskonnon koti: hindulaisuuden, buddhalaisuuden ja jainalaisuuden. Se on intohimoinen musiikin ja värien maa, ja siellä on paljon suurta rikkautta ja murskaavaa köyhyyttä. Vuosisatojen ajan Intia oli jakautunut keskenään taisteleviin kuningaskuntiin, jotka puolustautuivat myös ulkoisia valloittajia vastaan. 1100-luvulla jaa. Intian valtasivat muslimit. 1600-luvun alkupuolella saapuivat englantilaiset, jotka ketkun diplomatian ja teknologisen ylivoimansa ansiosta onnistuivat valtaamaan pirstaleisen maanne. Englanti jatkoi vallankahvassa kahden sadan vuoden ajan, kunnes intialaisten kansallistunne nostatti rauhanomaisimman vastarinnan historiassa, joka johti maan itsenäistymiseen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Gandhi, kansanne toivoo teidän nostattavan kansanne uuteen kukoistukseen! Kykenettekö auttamaan kansaanne huomaamaan heidän potentiaalinsa, jotta heistä tulisi jälleen maailman kulttuurin, taiteen ja uskonnon keskus? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_INDIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Intia</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_IROQUOIS_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdys jalo Hiawatha, mahtavan irokeesikansojen hallitsija! Kansanne on pitkään asunut lähellä pyhää Ontarion järveä, joka nykyisin tunnetaan osana Pohjois-Amerikan New Yorkin osavaltiota. Historian hämärissä viisi kansaa - senecat, onondagat, mohawkit, cayugat ja oneidat - yhdistyivät Haudenosaunee-liitoksi, irokeeseiksi. Ilman kirjakielen apua liiton viisaat miehet loivat "Suuren rauhan lain", joka on toiminut mallina monille perustuslaille, Yhdysvalloista lähtien. Monien vuosien ajan kansanne taisteli mahtavia vihollisia, huroneja, sekä ranskalaisia ja englantilaisia tunkeutujia vastaan. Vähäisemmästä lukumäärästään ja kehittymättömämmistä aseistaan huolimatta irokeesit selvisivät ja kukoistivat aina siihen saakka, kunnes Yhdysvaltain armeija murskasi heidät.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi jalo Hiawatha! Kuulkaa kansanne huuto! He kutsuvat teidät johtamaan heitä rauhan että sodan aikana! Rakentakaa suuri pitkätalo yhdistämään heimot jälleen kerran. Otatteko tämän haasteen vastaan, suuri johtaja? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_IROQUOIS_TITLE">
			<Text>Irokeesit</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JAPAN_TITLE">
			<Text>Japani</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_MONGOLIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Mongolia</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_OTTOMANS_TITLE">
			<Text>Osmanit</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_PERSIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Persia</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ROME_TITLE">
			<Text>Rooma</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_RUSSIA_TITLE">
			<Text>Venäjä</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SIAM_TITLE">
			<Text>Siam</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SONGHAI_TITLE">
			<Text>Songhai</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SPAIN_TITLE">
			<Text>Espanja</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_UNITEDSTATES_TEXT">
			<Text>Tervehdys presidentti Washingon! Olet teollisen Amerikan kansakunnan johtaja. Muodustuttuaan vallankumouksesta 1700-luvulla nuori kansakuntamme kärsi kauhean sisällissodan, joka lähestulkoon sai valtakunnan jakautumaan. Ja silti vain muutamia vuosia myöhemmin 1900-luvulla Yhdysvallat saavutti valtansa huipun ja nousi voittajana kahdesta kauheasta sodasta, jotka toivat lopun kovin monelle muulle mahtavalle valtiolle.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Yhdysvallat on maahanmuuttajien valtakunta, joka on täynnä optimismia ja päättäväisyyttä. Heiltä puuttuu vain johtaja, joka voisi tuoda heidän lupauksensa kukoistukseen. Presidentti Washington, voitteko te johdattaa amerikkalaiset suuruuteen? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_UNITEDSTATES_TITLE">
			<Text>Yhdysvallat</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_1066_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_VIKING_TEXT">
			<Text>SKENAARION KUVAUS[NEWLINE]Tervehdys tavatessamme, suuri viikinkien johtaja! Englannin kuningas Edvard Tunnustaja on kuollut. Saksien Harald Godwininpoika, Edvardin alainen jaarli, on nopeasti kahminut kruunun itselleen. Moinen tempaus on heikoilla kantimilla, sillä niin Normandian Vilhelmillä, Norjan Harald Ankaralla kuin Tanskan Svenillä on perusteltu oikeus tulla kruunatuksi. Kykenetkö pukemaan yllesi viikinkiherran viitan ja nousemaan Englannin seuraavaksi kuninkaaksi? Täytä laivasi ja osoita maailmalle oikeutesi olla Odinin valittu soturi.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VOITTAMISEN EHDOT[NEWLINE]Domesdayn kirja (kansallinen ihme) tulee rakentaa Lontooseen ennen skenaarion ajan päättymistä. Sinun tarvitsee rakentaa 6 Domesdayn konnunkäräjää anglosaksien alunperin hallitsemiin englantilaiskaupunkeihin, jotta voit tuottaa Domesdayn kirjan. Konnunkäräjiä voi rakentaa kaupunkeihin, jotka ovat korkeintaan 8 ruudun päässä Lontoosta.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]ERIKOISSÄÄNNÖT[NEWLINE]Kaikki neljä suurvaltaa ovat sodassa keskenään koko skenaarion ajan. Tiede-, linjaus- ja onnellisuusjärjestelmät ovat poissa käytöstä. Et saa uutta tekniikkaa tai sosiaalisia linjauksia pelin aikana. Sinun ei tarvitse välittää hallitsemiesi tai valtaamiesi kaupunkien onnellisuudesta. Saat kaupunkivaltioiden yksiköt hallintaasi liiton ajaksi muodostaessasi liiton heidän kanssaan. Kaikki yksiköt pystyvät puolustautumaan uitossa.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ASSYRIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Kansa kumartaa syvään teidän arvostettua tahtoanne, oi viisas ja maineikas Assyrian kuningas Assurbanipal. Kautta maailman teidät tunnetaan niin oppineena kuin soturina, ja silti legendat paljastavat vain pienen säihkeen todellisesta suuruudestanne. Vaikka pelkkä ajatus valloitusaikeistanne sai vihollisenne perääntymään, olivat älylliset tavoitteet todellinen ylpeydenaiheenne. Tiedonjanonne sai teidät perustamaan Niniven kuninkaallisen kirjaston, joka edusti yhtä antiikin merkittävimmistä tekstikokoelmista - varmistaen perintösi yhtenä Assyrian merkittävimmistä kuninkaista.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oi viisas ja peloton kuningas, on jälleen tullut aika palauttaa Assyyria suurimpaan kukoistukseensa. Kykenettekö jälleen keräämään kaikkien maailman kansojen tietouden ja historian? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_AUSTRIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Oi jalo ja hyveellinen Maria Teresia, pyhä roomalais-saksalainen keisaritar ja Itävallan kuningatar, kansa kumartuu armolliseen tahtoonne. Isänne kuningas Kaarle VI:n kuoleman jälkeen peritte Itävallan valtaistuimen huomattavan epävakauden aikoina, mutta tyhjät kassakirstut ja heikentynyt armeija eivät kyenneet kitkemään kunnianhimoanne. Lähes välittömästi kokemastanne perimyssodasta huolimatta kykenitte puskemaan kilpailijanne syrjään ja nimeämällä Frans Stefanin kanssahallitsijaksi vahvistitte paikkanne Pyhän saksalais-roomalaisen keisarikunnan keisarinnana. Valtanne aikana ohjasitte Itävallan uudistusten teille - vahvistaen armeijaa, palauttaen rahat kirstuihin ja kohentaen kuningaskunnan koulutusjärjestelmää.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Te suuri kuningatar, ylväs ja arvostettu, on tullut jälleen aika nostattaa ja ohjata kuningaskuntaa jälleen kerran. Kykenettekö palauttamaan kansanne vaurauden ja loiston huipulle? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_BRAZIL_TEXT">
			<Text>Kaikki kunnia arvostetuimmalle ja ylevämielisimmälle hallitsijalle, Brasilian Pedro II:lle. Kiitos syvän ymmärtämyksen ja rikkoutumattoman kunnian hallitsitte Brasilian valtakuntaa yli 50 vuotta, taaten maalle kestävän rauhan ja vaurauden. Maineenne ankarana mutta reiluna johtajana ei tullut koskaan haastetuksi, sillä järkkymätön omistautumisenne brasilialaisille toi toivoa ja vahvisti kuningaskunnan aseman Etelä-Amerikassa. Opetukselliset tavoitteenne ja vankkumaton sananvapauden puolustuksenne johtivat lukuisien korkeampien opinahjojen muodostumiseen, vahvistaen Brasilian kansallistuntoa.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Kunniakas Pedro, kansanne odottaa jo tohkeissaan teidän johtavan heidät rauhaisiin aikoihin jolloin kävelitte heidän kanssaan, kuunnellen heidän tarinansa ja vahvistaen heidän käsitystään loistavasta tulevaisuudesta. Johdatteko jälleen kuningaskuntanne vaurauteen? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_BYZANTIUM_TEXT">
			<Text>All hail the most magnificent and magnanimous Empress Theodora, beloved of Byzantium and of Rome! From the lowly ranks of actress and courtesan you became the most powerful woman in the Roman Empire, consort to Justinian I. Starting in the late 520's AD, you joined your husband in a series of important spiritual and legal reforms, creating many laws which elevated the status of and promoted equal treatment of women in the empire. You also aided in the restoration and construction of many aqueducts, bridges, and churches across Constantinople, culminating in the creation of the Hagia Sophia, one of the most splendid architectural wonders of the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beautiful Empress, Byzantium is in need of your wisdom and strength - her people are lost without your light to lead them. The Byzantine Empire may have fallen once, but its spirit is still intact waiting to be reborn anew. Can you return Byzantium to the heights of glory it once enjoyed? Can you create a civilization to stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_CARTHAGE_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings and salutations to you, revered Queen Dido, founder of the legendary kingdom of Carthage. Chronicled by the words of the great poet Virgil, your husband Acerbas was murdered at the hands of your own brother, King Pygmalion of Tyre, who subsequently claimed the treasures of Acerbas that were now rightfully yours. Fearing the lengths from which your brother would pursue this vast wealth, you and your compatriots sailed for new lands. Arriving on the shores of North Africa, you tricked the local king with the simple manipulation of an ox hide, laying out a vast expanse of territory for your new home, the future kingdom of Carthage.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Clever and inquisitive Dido, the world longs for a leader who can provide a shelter from the coming storm, guided by brilliant intuition and cunning. Can you lead the people in the creation of a new kingdom to rival that of once mighty Carthage? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_CELTS_TEXT">
			<Text>Eternal glory and praise for you, fierce and vengeful Warrior Queen! In a time dominated by men, you not only secured your throne and sovereign rule, but also successfully defied the power of the Roman Empire.  After suffering terrible punishment and humiliation at the hand of the Roman invaders, you rallied your people in a bloody and terrifying revolt. Legions fell under your chariot wheels and the city of London burned. While in the end the Romans retained ownership of the isles, you alone made Nero consider withdrawing all troops and leaving Briton forever.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh sleeping lioness, your people desire that you rise and lead them again in the calling that is your namesake.  Will you meet their challenge on the open field and lead the Celts to everlasting victory? Will you restore your lands and build an empire to stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ETHIOPIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings be upon you, honorable and righteous Emperor of Ethiopia, Haile Selassie. Your legacy as one of Ethiopia's greatest rulers, and as the spiritual leader to the Rastafarian movement, is outshone only by the influence you had on diplomacy and political cooperation throughout the world. In introducing Ethiopia's first written constitution, you planted the seeds of democracy that would take root over the coming years, and your infinitely wise grasp of global affairs secured Ethiopia's place as a charter member of the United Nations. Spearheading efforts to reform and modernize the nation during your reign, you changed the course of Ethiopian history forever.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Revered king, your composed demeanor once protected the people from the many conflicts that plague the nations of men, and the kingdom looks to you to assure peace once again. Will you lead the people with courage and authority, moving forward into a new age? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_HUNS_TEXT">
			<Text>Your men stand proudly to greet you, Great Attila, grand warrior and ruler of the Hunnic Empire.  Together with your brother Bleda you expanded the boundaries of your empire, becoming the most powerful and frightening force of the 5th century.  You bowed the Eastern Roman Emperors to your will and took kingdom after kingdom along the Danube and Nisava Rivers.  As the sovereign ruler of the Huns, you marched your army across Europe into Gaul, planning to extend your already impressive lands all the way to the Atlantic Ocean.  Your untimely death led to the quick disintegration and downfall of your empire, but your name and deeds have created an everlasting legacy for your people.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Fearsome General, your people call for the recreation of a new Hunnic Empire, one which will make the exploits and histories of the former seem like the faded dreamings of a dying sun.  Will you answer their call to regain your rightful prominence and glory?  Will you mount your steadfast steed and lead your armies to victory?  Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_INDONESIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Honor be with you, oh great hero Gajah Mada, prime minister of Majapahit and unifier of the Indonesian archipelago. The stories of your heroism on the battlefield are bested only by the legends of your sworn oath to unite the far-flung islands of Indonesia under one banner. Serving your queen and empire with loyalty, you not only strove to fulfill your oath and conquered any who stood in your path, but you succeeded in capturing what was then the entirety of the known archipelago, the first to unite what is today modern Indonesia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty warrior Gajah Mada, your people yearn for a strong leader who can return them to prosperity! Will you set out to conquer the neighboring kingdoms, further expanding the glory of your empire? Will you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JAPAN_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings upon you noble Oda Nobunaga, ruler of the land where the sun rises - may you long walk among its flowering blossoms. You are the ruler of Japan, the land of the Rising Sun. The Japanese are an island people, proud and pious with a rich culture of arts and letters. Their civilization stretches back thousands of years, years of bloody warfare, expansion and isolation, great wealth and great poverty. In addition to their prowess on the field of battle, your people are also immensely industrious, and their technological innovation and mighty factories are the envy of lesser people everywhere.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Legendary daimyo, will you grab the reins of destiny?  Will you bring your family and people honor and glory? Will you once again pick up sword and shield and march to triumph?  Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_KOREA_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings to you, exalted King Sejong the Great, servant to the people and protector of the Choson Dynasty. Your glorious vision of prosperity and overwhelming benevolence towards the common man made you the most beloved of all Korean kings. From the earliest days of your reign, the efforts you took to provide a fair and just society for all were surpassed only by the technological advancements spurred onwards by your unquenched thirst for knowledge. Guided by your wisdom, the scholars of the Jade Hall developed Korea's first written language, Hangul, bringing the light of literature and science to the masses after centuries of literary darkness.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Honorable Sejong, once more the people look to you for guidance! Will you rise to the occasion, bringing harmony and understanding to the people? Can you once again advance your kingdom's standing to such wondrous heights? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_MAYA_TEXT">
			<Text>Your people kneel before you, exalted King Pacal the Great, favored son of the gods and shield to the citizens of the Palenque domain. After years of strife at the hands of your neighboring rivals, you struck back at the enemies of your people, sacrificing their leaders in retribution for the insults dealt to your predecessors. The glory of Palenque was restored only by the guidance afforded by your wisdom, as you orchestrated vast reconstruction efforts within the city, creating some of the greatest monuments and architecture your people- and the world -have ever known.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Illustrious King, your people once again look to you for leadership and counsel in the coming days. Will you channel the will of the gods and restore your once proud kingdom to its greatest heights? Will you build new monuments to forever enshrine the memories of your people? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_MONGOLIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings, oh Great Temujin, immortal Emperor of the mighty Mongol Empire! Your fists shatter the walls of cities, and your voice brings despair to your enemies. Oh Khan, you united the warring tribes of northern Asia into mighty people, creating the greatest cavalry force the world has ever witnessed! Your people's cunning diplomacy divided their enemies, making them weak and helpless before Mongolia's conquering armies. In a few short years your people's soldiers conquered most of China and Eastern Asia. And the empire continued to grow, until it reached west into Europe and south to Korea. Indeed, it was the greatest empire ever seen, dwarfing those pathetic conquests of the Romans or the Greeks.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Temujin, your people call upon you once more to lead them to battle and conquest! Will the world once again tremble at the thunderous sound of your cavalry sweeping down from the steppes? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_MOROCCO_TEXT">
			<Text>The people of Morocco await your guidance, great Sultan Ahmad al-Mansur of the Saadi Dynasty. Well known for your skill as both a negotiator and a diplomat, your careful words allowed for the forging of new alliances, securing the sovereignty of your nation and its people for decades. And still, when words failed, you found equal success in conquest, leading the Moroccan armies to victory on the battlefield while greatly expanding the grasp of your empire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Wise and respected Sultan, the people look to you for leadership. Can your skill in diplomacy match that of your rivals, or will you meet them sword in hand? Your once great kingdom yearns for that former glory -Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_NETHERLANDS_TEXT">
			<Text>Hail stalwart Prince William of Orange, liberator of the Netherlands and hero to the Dutch people. It was your courageous effort in the 1568 rebellion against Spanish dominion that led the Dutch to freedom, and ultimately resulted in the Eighty Years' War. Your undertaking allowed for the creation of one of Europe's first modern republics, the Seven United Provinces. You gave your life to the rebellion, falling at the hands of an assassin in 1584, but your death would only serve to embolden the people's charge, and your legacy as "Father of the Fatherland" will stand as a symbol of Dutch independence for all time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Brave prince, the people again yearn for the wise stewardship your wisdom afforded them. Can you once again secure the sovereignty of your kingdom and lead your people to greatness? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_OTTOMANS_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings of God be upon you, oh Great Emperor Suleiman! Your power, wealth and generosity awe the world! Truly are you called "Magnificent!" Your empire began in Bithynia, a small country in eastern Anatolia in the 12th century. Taking advantage of the decline of the great Seljuk Sultanate of Rum, King Osman I of Bithynia expanded west into Anatolia. Over the next century your subjects brought down the empire of Byzantium, taking its holdings in Turkey and then the Balkans. In the mid-fifteenth century the Ottomans captured ancient Constantinople, gaining control of the strategic link between Europe and the Middle East. Your people's empire would continue to expand for centuries, at its height governing much of North Africa, the Middle East, and Eastern Europe.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty Suleiman, heed the call of your people! Bring your empire back to the height of its power and glory, and once again the world will look upon your greatness with awe and admiration. Will you accept the challenge, Great Emperor? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_PERSIA_TEXT">
			<Text>The blessings of Heaven be upon you, beloved King Darius of Persia! You lead a strong and wise people. In the morning of the world, the great Persian leader Cyrus revolted against the mighty Median empire, and by 550 BC the Medes were no more. Through cunning diplomacy and military prowess Great Cyrus conquered wealthy Lydia and powerful Babylon, his son conquering proud Egypt some years later. Over time Persian might expanded into far-away Macedonia, on the very door of the upstart Greek city-states. Long would Persia prosper, until the upstart villain Alexander of Macedon destroyed the great empire in one shocking campaign.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Darius, your people look to you to once again bring back the days of power and glory for Persia! The empire of your ancestors must emerge again, to triumph over its foes and to bring peace and order to the world. Oh King, will you answer the call? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_POLAND_TEXT">
			<Text>All Hail noble King Casimir the Great, protector and sovereign of the Kingdom of Poland. You ascended to the throne during a time of great turmoil, with the nation's economy in shambles and its people demoralized by the wars of your predecessor. And yet, your reign marked the beginning of a new era, with affluence and security afforded only by way of your careful governance. Among your most notable achievements, the code of laws you established gave legal authority to many of the accepted customs of the time, strengthening the nation.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Honored king Casimir, the people have long admired the steady hand of governance you wield. Can you return your kingdom and its subjects to a golden age of prosperity? Will you conquer all those who oppose you, or strive for peaceful relations? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_POLYNESIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings and blessings be upon you, Kamehameha the Great, chosen by the heavens to unite your scattered peoples.  Oh mighty King, you were the first to bring the Big Island of Hawai'i under one solitary rule in 1791 AD. This was followed with the merging of all the remaining islands under your standard in 1810. As the first King of Hawai'i, you standardized the legal and taxation systems and instituted the Mamalahoe Kanawai, an edict protecting civilians in times of war. You ensured the continued unification and sovereignty of the islands by your strong laws and deeds, even after your death in 1819.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh wise and exalted King, your people wish for a kingdom of their own once more and require a leader of unparalleled greatness! Will you answer their call and don the mantle of the Lion of the Pacific? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_PORTUGAL_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings be upon you, most gracious Queen Maria, protector and sovereign of the Portuguese people. As the first ever Queen regnant of Portugal, it was your wise stewardship that protected the royal court from the incursions of Napoleon, establishing a safe haven in Brazil to preserve the integrity of Portuguese rule. Despite struggling with illness throughout your reign, your efforts to ensure Portugal's close cooperation with Brazil are credited with helping that state gain its eventual independence - and for this you will always be admired and respected by the people of both nations.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh noble and pious queen, will you once again guide the kingdom of Portugal in the spirit of cooperation and prosperity? Will you establish a new legacy, one that will surpass all those who came before you? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ROME_TEXT">
			<Text>The blessings of the gods be upon you, Caesar Augustus, Emperor of Rome and all her holdings. Your empire was the greatest and longest-lived of all in Western Civilization, and your people single-handedly have shaped its culture, law, art, and warfare like none other, before or since. Through years of glorious conquest, Rome came to dominate all the lands of the Mediterranean, from Spain in the west to Syria in the east, and her dominion would eventually expand to cover much of England and Northern Germany. Roman art and architecture still awe and inspire the world, and she remains the envy of all of the lesser civilizations who have followed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]O mighty Emperor, your people turn to you to once more reclaim the glory of Rome. Will you see to it that your empire rises again, bringing peace and order to all?  Will you make Rome once again center of the world? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_RUSSIA_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings upon thee, Your Imperial Majesty Catherine, wondrous Empress of all the Russias.  At your command lies the largest country in the world. Mighty Russia stretches from the Pacific Ocean in the east to the Baltic Sea in the west. Despite wars, droughts, and every manner of disaster the heroic Russian people survive and prosper, their artists and scientists among the best in the world. The Empire today remains one of the strongest ever seen in human history - a true superpower, with the greatest destructive force ever devised at her command.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Catherine, your people look to you to bring forth glorious days for Russia and her people, to revitalize the land and recapture the wonder of the Enlightenment. Will you lead your people once more into greatness? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SHOSHONE_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings be upon you, wise and fearsome Chief Pocatello, revered leader of the Shoshone people. As the young chieftain of the Shoshone, you rose to face a wave of encroaching American settlements across the western United States.  Forced to defend the Shoshone ancestral lands from a seemingly endless stream of new emigrants, your war band struck fear into those who would claim the sacred lands of your people. After years of strife, you skillfully avoided a direct conflict with the armies of the U.S. government, and negotiated a series of treaties in the hopes of establishing a lasting peace for the Shoshone.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Most esteemed Pocatello, your people once again look to you for guidance. Will you conquer your enemies, driving them far from your lands? Or will you seek out peaceful diplomacy and trade? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SIAM_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings to you, great King Ramkhamhaeng, leader of the glorious Siamese people! O mighty King, your people bow down before you in awe and fear! You are the ruler of Siam, an ancient country in the heart of Southeast Asia. Siam is a beautiful and mysterious land. Surrounded by foes, beset by bloody war and grinding poverty, the clever and loyal Siamese people have endured and triumphed. King Ramkhamhaeng, your empire was once part of the Khmer Empire, until the 13th century AD, when your ancestors revolted, forming the small Sukhothai kingdom. Through successful battle and cunning diplomacy the tiny kingdom grew into a mighty empire, an empire which would dominate Southeast Asia for more than a century![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh wise and puissant King Ramkhamhaeng, your people need you to once again lead them to greatness! Can you use your wits and strength of arms to protect your people and defeat your foes? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SONGHAI_TEXT">
			<Text>May the blessings of God, who is greatest of all, be upon you Askia, leader of the Songhai people!  For many years your kingdom was a vassal state of the mighty West African state of Mali, until the middle of the 14th century, when king Sunni Ali Ber wrested independence from the Mali, conquering much territory and fighting off numerous foes who sought to destroy him. Ultimately, his conquest of the wealthy cities of Timbuktu and Jenne gave the growing Songhai empire the economic power to survive for some 100 years, until the empire was destroyed by foes with advanced technology - muskets against spearmen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]King Askia, your people look to you to lead them to glory. To make them powerful and wealthy, to keep them supplied with the weapons they need to defeat any foe. Can you save them from destruction, oh King? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SPAIN_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessed Isabella, Servant of God, Holy Queen of Castile and Le�n, your people greet and welcome you! You are the ruler of Spain, a beautiful and ancient country at the crossroads of the world between Europe and Africa, one shore on the Mediterranean and the other on the mighty Atlantic Ocean. The Spanish are a multicultural people, with roots in the Muslim and Christian world. A seafaring race, Spanish explorers found and conquered much of the New World, and for many centuries its gold and silver brought Spain unrivaled wealth and power, making the Spanish court the envy of the world.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]O fair and virtuous Isabella, will you rebuild the Spanish Empire and show the world again the greatness of your people?  Will you take up the mantle of the holy monarchy and vanquish your foes under Heaven's watchful eyes?  Your adoring subjects await your command. Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SWEDEN_TEXT">
			<Text>All hail the transcendent King Gustavus Adolphus, founder of the Swedish Empire and her most distinguished military tactician. It was during your reign that Sweden emerged as one of the greatest powers in Europe, due in no small part to your wisdom, both on and off the battlefield. As king, you initiated a number of domestic reforms that ensured the economic stability and prosperity of your people. As the general who came to be known as the "Lion of the North," your visionary designs in warfare gained the admiration of military commanders the world over. Thanks to your triumphs in the Thirty Years' War, you were assured a legacy as one of history's greatest generals.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh noble King, the people long for your prudent leadership, hopeful that once again they will see your kingdom rise to glory. Will you devise daring new strategies, leading your armies to victory on the theater of war? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_VENICE_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings, most astute Doge Enrico Dandolo of Venice, master of statecraft and shrewd negotiator. Although you rose to power late in life, old age did little to slow your cunning or ambition, as you deftly managed the bustling commercial center of Venice during a time of great instability. In aligning yourself with the Fourth Crusade, you carefully gained a strategic advantage and used the Crusaders to reacquire lost territory for Venice. Your role in guiding the Crusaders during the sacking of Constantinople led to an even greater expansion of your power, and secured your legacy throughout history.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Most insightful and cunning Doge, Venice once again requires the service of a skilled leader, one who can bring the republic back to the forefront of world affairs. Can you establish your nation through careful trade, or will you work to conquer your enemies through diplomacy? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ZULU_TEXT">
			<Text>Your people kneel before you, great warrior Shaka of the Zulu Kingdom. As you rose from a place of exile to become the true leader of the Zulus, you ushered in changes throughout the Zulu society, implementing new laws and cultural reforms that strengthened the position of your kingdom. However, it was your tenacity in the art of war that truly established your reputation, as your tactics and strategies on the battlefield forever changed the face of combat across the plains of southern Africa.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Most formidable king, your people once again long for the unity and strength your leadership afforded them. Can you return the Zulu kingdom to such great prominence? Kykenettekö luomaan kansakunnan, joka kestää ajasta iäisyyteen?</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_KOREA_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_CHINA_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Blessings be upon you great one -- may the mandate of heaven guide you through these difficult times, for the winds of change are upon us, sweeping over East Asia. The victories of the great Japanese warlord Toyotomi Hideyoshi have at long last unified that island nation. Confident in Japan's new gunpowder weaponry, Hideyoshi now casts his eye to the west. Both the venerable Ming Dynasty in China and their ally the Choson Dynasty in Korea must be vigilant! And there is news of a new power taking shape to the north on the Manchurian Plain. Ready your soldiers, your horsemen, and your navies: all forms of weapons and technology must be brought to bear in the coming struggle for control of the lands surrounding the Yellow Sea![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Japan or the Manchu win by conquering both Seoul and Beijing. China and Korea win by controlling all their original cities any time after the year 1600. If none of these conditions occur, the winner is the civ with the most points when the 100 turns are complete. Note that there are extra points earned for each enemy unit killed and for control of Seoul and Beijing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Buy policies at the start to balance your happiness and gold. The only civ that can build new cities is the Manchu. Korea and China are an allied team that starts the game at war with Japan. Science has been turned off.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_KOREA_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_JAPAN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Blessings be upon you great one -- may the mandate of heaven guide you through these difficult times, for the winds of change are upon us, sweeping over East Asia. The victories of the great Japanese warlord Toyotomi Hideyoshi have at long last unified that island nation. Confident in Japan's new gunpowder weaponry, Hideyoshi now casts his eye to the west. Both the venerable Ming Dynasty in China and their ally the Choson Dynasty in Korea must be vigilant! And there is news of a new power taking shape to the north on the Manchurian Plain. Ready your soldiers, your horsemen, and your navies: all forms of weapons and technology must be brought to bear in the coming struggle for control of the lands surrounding the Yellow Sea![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Japan or the Manchu win by conquering both Seoul and Beijing. China and Korea win by controlling all their original cities any time after the year 1600. If none of these conditions occur, the winner is the civ with the most points when the 100 turns are complete. Note that there are extra points earned for each enemy unit killed and for control of Seoul and Beijing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Buy policies at the start to balance your happiness and gold. The only civ that can build new cities is the Manchu. Korea and China are an allied team that starts the game at war with Japan. Science has been turned off.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_KOREA_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_KOREA_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Blessings be upon you great one -- may the mandate of heaven guide you through these difficult times, for the winds of change are upon us, sweeping over East Asia. The victories of the great Japanese warlord Toyotomi Hideyoshi have at long last unified that island nation. Confident in Japan's new gunpowder weaponry, Hideyoshi now casts his eye to the west. Both the venerable Ming Dynasty in China and their ally the Choson Dynasty in Korea must be vigilant! And there is news of a new power taking shape to the north on the Manchurian Plain. Ready your soldiers, your horsemen, and your navies: all forms of weapons and technology must be brought to bear in the coming struggle for control of the lands surrounding the Yellow Sea![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Japan or the Manchu win by conquering both Seoul and Beijing. China and Korea win by controlling all their original cities any time after the year 1600. If none of these conditions occur, the winner is the civ with the most points when the 100 turns are complete. Note that there are extra points earned for each enemy unit killed and for control of Seoul and Beijing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Buy policies at the start to balance your happiness and gold. The only civ that can build new cities is the Manchu. Korea and China are an allied team that starts the game at war with Japan. Science has been turned off.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_KOREA_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_MONGOLIA_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Blessings be upon you great one -- may the mandate of heaven guide you through these difficult times, for the winds of change are upon us, sweeping over East Asia. The victories of the great Japanese warlord Toyotomi Hideyoshi have at long last unified that island nation. Confident in Japan's new gunpowder weaponry, Hideyoshi now casts his eye to the west. Both the venerable Ming Dynasty in China and their ally the Choson Dynasty in Korea must be vigilant! And there is news of a new power taking shape to the north on the Manchurian Plain. Ready your soldiers, your horsemen, and your navies: all forms of weapons and technology must be brought to bear in the coming struggle for control of the lands surrounding the Yellow Sea![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Japan or the Manchu win by conquering both Seoul and Beijing. China and Korea win by controlling all their original cities any time after the year 1600. If none of these conditions occur, the winner is the civ with the most points when the 100 turns are complete. Note that there are extra points earned for each enemy unit killed and for control of Seoul and Beijing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Buy policies at the start to balance your happiness and gold. The only civ that can build new cities is the Manchu. Korea and China are an allied team that starts the game at war with Japan. Science has been turned off.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Greetings to you, renowned Captain of science and industry!  The advent of steam power has revolutionized the world.  It is a time of discovery, fueled by newfound resources and brilliant inventions.  Great airships trek across the skies, marking their trails with black smoke.  Civilizations are propelled towards a bright future, but competition is fierce.  Resources are scarce, and technological secrets are carefully guarded.  You and your rivals must expand your empires across the globe to meet growing needs in the name of progress.  Can you harness the power of steam technology and bring your people to greatness?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Empires compete in the domains of Military, Culture, Industry, Commerce, and Labor.  Be the best in a domain to earn an Honourable Title.  To see the specifics of each Title, and monitor your progress, check the League of Empires screen.  The first empire to hold three or more Titles wins the game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Players begin with all technologies up through Steam Power.  The tech tree after Steam Power has been altered significantly, giving players the ability to construct Airships, Landships, and new buildings.  Barbarians ("Luddites") are enabled, but do not have access to advanced units.  Social Policies have been rearranged.  Religion has been disabled, as have religious and militaristic city-states.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SCRAMBLE_AFRICA_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Europeans had claimed most of the native lands elsewhere, but not the dark continent of Africa. Driven by a sense of adventure, a desire for wealth, and the thirst for knowledge, explorers and settlers scrambled into Africa from north and west. There they encountered lost kingdoms, exotic beasts and native empires that challenged their dreams of colonization. Can you claim the riches of Africa as a European? Or will you try and repulse the interlopers?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Achieve high score after 100 turns. Find each Natural Wonder for +4 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness. Europeans (Belgium, England, France, Germany, Italy, Portugal) earn VP if they are the first to discover a Natural Wonder and for recovering Artifacts. Earning [ICON_GOLD] Gold scores VP for North Africans (Egypt, Morocco, Ottomans); Sub-Saharans (Ethiopia, Boers, Zulu) score for [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. Control of Suez and the Longest Rail line between two cities also scores VP. Land is worth twice as much.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]The interior of Africa changes each time you play. Only the European civs can embark, build Railroads, and dig for Artifacts, and they cannot declare war on each other. Likewise, the North African civs also cannot declare war on each other.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_POLYNESIAN_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_POLYNESIAN_TEXT">
			<Text>Aloha, great Polynesian king!  You currently rule over one of the great islands of your people.  Though life on your lush, tropical paradise is an idyllic one, you thirst for even more greatness across the waves.  Your people have invented wayfinding, a sophisticated navigation system that relies on your knowledge of the stars, the birds, and the currents of the mighty Pacific Ocean.  Your bold navigators are ready to strike out hundreds of miles across the open ocean in their double-hulled canoes, questing for new islands to colonize.  Can you successfully traverse the deadly waves and find a foothold beyond your original coastal home?  Can you expand your island's culture and dominate the mighty Pacific?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization who can adopt all social policies to become the dominant culture in Polynesia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]There are all new tech and social policy trees appropriate to the scenario's Pacific Ocean setting. Each of the four major civilizations starts with a unique trait and can gain the usual Polynesian unique bonuses (Moai improvement and Maori Warrior unit) through research. Grow your empire as large as you want; the cost of social policies does NOT increase based on number of cities in the empire.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_AZTECS_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_ENGLAND_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_FRANCE_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_INCA_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_IROQUOIS_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_NEWWORLD_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NEWWORLD_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_SPAIN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The year is 1492. To the courts of England, France, and Spain come intrepid explorers, anxious to voyage across the Atlantic in search of a western route to China and the Indies. Will they find a new trade route and uncover untold riches from the Asian shores? Or will they perhaps run aground on undiscovered lands along their way? Will native peoples be receptive to the knowledge and trade prospects presented to them, or will they fight against the invaders of their homeland? What riches, fame, and opportunities await those who brave the unknown waters? What path will you choose? Who will prevail in the struggle for supremacy over this New World?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory goes to the first civilization to reach a score of 1000 VP. You earn bonus VP for reaching China with an exploring Caravel and for returning Treasure units to your capital. Play as many times as you like trying each of the six civs: the map of America changes each time you start a new game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]All naval combat units are afflicted with Scurvy, a "promotion" that may cause them to lose health each turn they end outside friendly lands. Build the Navigation School national wonder to combat this malady. European powers may not declare war on one another until one of them researches the Piracy technology. Treasure units are created when cities are razed or from the El Dorado and Potosi natural wonders (if they exist on this map). Move these civilian units to your capital to earn gold and VP.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MONGOL_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_MONGOLIA_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]All hail the mighty Khan, the new ruler of the united tribes of the Central Asian plateau! You have brought the Merkits, Naimans, Keraits, and Tatars under your domain, joining them with your own faithful Mongol Keshiks. Now that you command 5 tribes of horsemen, it is time to bring the rest of Eurasia under the Mongol yoke. But don't think this is necessarily an easy task - you must keep your greedy clansmen happy.  They have promised to stay faithful to your Yassa code only if you can provide them adequate spoils of war. So there is no time to waste: journey out across the steppes and let your conquests begin![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory is yours if you can conquer 4 or more major civilizations before 100 turns have elapsed. (On Difficulty Levels higher than Prince, you will need to conquer more than 4.) Tarry longer than the allotted time and your compatriots will grow impatient, causing your once mighty empire to dissolve into squabbling fiefdoms.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]The spoils you receive from conquest will be numerous and varied, all providing needed boosts and resources to continue pushing forward.  For example, the troops of militaristic city states will join your forces.  A cultural city state will provide a free social policy. And a maritime city state will provide extra gold for your treasury.  Best of all, for conquering a major civilization you will receive a free technology and even greater riches!</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MEDIEVAL_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The Great Schism has divided the Christian church into east and west. All attempts to reconcile Byzantium and Rome have failed. Meanwhile the Islamic armies of the Great Turk threaten Constantinople with capture. In response, Pope Urban II issues a call for a crusade to bolster the Byzantines and liberate the Holy Land. The stage is set for a dramatic battle between the faiths. With such bloodshed on the horizon, will you be able to preserve civilization as we know it and lead the world into the glory of the Renaissance?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory is awarded based on score after 200 turns. Earn special scenario VP as follows:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Holy City Control: Control (or be allied with) the Holy City for your religion or Jerusalem (10 VP per turn).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Holy Roman Emperor: Win the election by receiving the most votes from all powers and City-States (250 VP per election).[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]New World: Send Caravels west after researching Exploration.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Religious War: Capture cities following a different religion.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Three religions are established before the game starts: Catholicism (Holy City is Vatican City), Orthodoxy (Holy City is Constantinople) and Islam (Holy City is Mecca). Control your Holy City (or Jerusalem) to gain the benefits of the Founder beliefs for your religion.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_FOR_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]The Roman Empire, now split into West and East, has ruled the known world for nearly a millennium. But in this 4th century AD, the empire's borders are being overrun by barbarian leaders carving out their own kingdoms as Rome's might falters. Meanwhile a great storm gathers to the northeast as Attila and his Huns begin an overpowering wave of pillage and conquest. Choose your side, gather your courage, and fight to decide the next thousand years of history.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Victory revolves around controlling cities of the three empires: Western Rome, Eastern Rome, and Sassanid Persia. Empires gain victory points each turn for control of each imperial city (the Sassanids get 50% more). Barbarian civs gain victory points for capturing cities controlled by an empire. Larger cities are worth more points. Victory goes to the civilization with the most victory points at the end of 70 turns.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Units under Barbarian civ control have no unit maintenance. The Roman Empires may not sell buildings. There are three separate Social Policy trees available in the game. One is only available to the Eastern and Western Roman Empires, one only for the Sassanids, and one for the Barbarian powers. The Roman policy tree works backwards, in that you receive penalties instead of benefits for each policy chosen.</Text>
		</Row><Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]April the 12th, 1861. Confederate mortars open fire on Fort Sumter in Charleston harbor, signaling the start of America's Civil War. President Abraham Lincoln issues a call for volunteers for 90-day enlistments, confident that the rebellion can be put down in short order. Jefferson Davis, newly elected President of the Confederates States, is equally optimistic. Davis boldly moves his government to Richmond, Virginia, just 100 miles from Washington, D.C.  Can you win the swift victory both sides are predicting? Or will this war test if a nation conceived in liberty can long endure?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Win by capturing your opponent's capital before time runs out.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]City razing and settlers are off. Only cities with one of these production buildings may create units: either the Arsenal (Infantry), Stable (Cavalry), Iron Works (Artillery), or Navy Yard (Naval Units). Capture enemy cities to control these production centers and the Manpower resource, necessary for Infantry units. All units of the player moving first receive just half their usual movement on the opening turn. Cities have no range strike and only minimal defense above the combat strength of any garrison. Great Generals' range increased to 5 and they are displaced to a nearby city rather than killed.</Text>
		</Row></Language_fi_FI>
</GameData>